ringaling.tv 2010-02-01

# Ringaling - Privacy Policy

This document declares the undertakings by Ringaling.tv in relation to its handling of your data.

Data Collection 

Ringaling.tv undertakes to collect your data by means that are: 

  * fair;
  * legal; and
  * transparent.  

If you visit Ringaling.tv's web-site, your web-browser automatically discloses, and Ringaling.tv's web-server automatically logs, the following information: the date and time, the IP address from which you issued the request, the type of browser and operating system you are using, the URL of any page that referred you to the page, the URL you requested, and whether your request was successful. This data may or may not be sufficient to identify you. 

Any additional data that you provide, e.g. in a web-form, may also be logged. This data may or may not be sufficient to identify you. 

Any additional data that your web-browser automatically provides may also be logged. This will be the case, for example, if your browser has previously been requested to store data on your computer in 'cookies' and submits them each time you request a web-page within a particular domain (such as Ringaling.tv). This data may or may not be sufficient to identify you.

If you disclose personal data to Ringaling.tv in conjunction with an identifier such as your name or your mobile/cellular telephone number, Ringaling.tv will collect this data. Moreover, any data that becomes available to Ringaling.tv through any of the means described in the preceding paragraphs may be able to be associated with that identifier. 

Where Ringaling.tv collects data from sources other than you, it undertakes:

  * to do so only by legal means;
  * to do so only with your Consent; and
  * to decare to you what sources it uses, and under what circumstances.  

Data Security

Ringaling.tv undertakes to store personally identifiable information (PII) in a manner that ensures security against unauthorised access, alteration or deletion, at a level commensurate with its sensitivity. 

Ringaling.tv undertakes to store personally identifiable information only in jurisdictions where data protections are at least equivalent to those required under the OECD Guidelines.

Ringaling.tv undertakes to transmit personally identifiable information in a manner that ensures security against unauthorised access, alteration or deletion, at a level commensurate with its sensitivity. 

Ringaling.tv undertakes to implement appropriate measures to ensure security of personally identifiable information against inappropriate behaviour by Ringaling.tv's staff-members and contractors. These include:

  * training for staff in relation to privacy;
  * access control, to limit access to personally identifiable information to those staff and contractors who have legitimate reasons to access it;
  * particularly in the case of sensitive data, audit trails of accesses, including the identities of staff and contractors accessing the data;
  * reminders to staff and contractors from time to time about the importance of data privacy, and the consequences of inappropriate behaviour;
  * declaration of appropriately strong sanctions that are to be applied in the event of inappropriate behaviour
  * clear communication of policies and sanctions; and
  * processes to audit, to investigate and to impose sanctions.  

Data Use

Use refers to the application of personally identifiable information by any part of Ringaling.tv, or any staff-member or contractor of Ringaling.tv in the course of their work.

Ringaling.tv undertakes to use PII only for:

  * the purposes for which it was collected;
  * such other purposes as are subsequently agreed between Ringaling.tv and You;
  * such additional purposes as may be required by law. In these circumstances, Ringaling.tv will take any reasonable steps available to it to communicate to You that the use has occurred, unless it is precluded from doing so by law; and
  * such additional purposes as are authorised by law (in particular to protect Ringaling.tv's interests, e.g. if it believes on reasonable grounds that You have failed to fulfil your undertakings to Ringaling.tv or have committed a breach of the criminal law).

Ringaling.tv undertakes to use personally identifiable information only if it has demonstrable relevance to the particular use to which it is being put. 

Ringaling.tv undertakes to use personally identifiable information in such a manner as to take into account the possibility that it is not of sufficient quality for the purpose, e.g. because it is inaccurate, out-of-date, incomplete, or out-of-context.

Data Disclosure

Disclosure refers to making personally identifiable information available to any party other than Ringaling.tv and You. The term disclosure may include many different conditions of data transfer, including selling, renting, trading, sharing and giving. 

Ringaling.tv undertakes to disclose personally identifiable information only under the following circumstances:

  * in the course of business being conducted between You and Ringaling.tv, where disclosure is necessary to a contractor, such as a transport company. Where personally identifiable information is disclosed in this way, Ringaling.tv undertakes to exercise control over Ringaling.tv's contractors to ensure that their actions are compliant with these Terms;
  * in other circumstances that are directly implied by the purpose agreed between You and Ringaling.tv at the time of data collection or subsequently. Where PII is disclosed in this way, Ringaling.tv undertakes to exercise control over Ringaling.tv's contractors to ensure that their actions are compliant with these Terms;
  * with your consent, or at your request;
  * where required by law, such as a provision of a statute, or a court order such as a search warrant or sub poena. In these circumstances, Ringaling.tv will take any reasonable steps available to it to communicate to You that the disclosure has occurred, unless it is precluded from doing so by law;
  * where permitted by law (e.g. the reporting of suspected breach of the criminal law to a law enforcement agency; and in an emergency, where Ringaling.tv believes on reasonable grounds that the disclosure of personally identifiable information will materially assist in the protection of the life of health of some person), provided that Ringaling.tv will apply due diligence to ensure that the exercise of the permission is justifiable.

In all cases, Ringaling.tv undertakes to disclose only such of personally identifiable information as is necessary in the particular circumstances.

Data Retention and Destruction 

Subject to the qualifications immediately below, Ringaling.tv undertakes:

  * to retain Personally identifiable information only as long as is consistent with its purpose; and
  * to destroy PII when its purpose has expired, and to do so in such a manner that PII is not subsequently capable of being recovered.
  * This undertaking is qualified as follows:
  * PII may be retained in Ringaling.tv's logs, backups and audit trails within short-term retention cycles that are devised to protect the company's operations. In such cases, PII will be destroyed in accordance with those cycles;
  * PII may be retained beyond the expiry of its purpose if that is required by law, such as a provision of a statute, or a court order such as a search warrant or sub poena, or a warning by a law enforcement agency that delivery of a court order is imminent. In these circumstances, Ringaling.tv: 1) will take any reasonable steps available to it to communicate to You that PII is being retained, unless it is precluded from doing so by law; and 2) will only retain PII while that provision is current, and will then destroy PII; 
  * PII may be retained beyond the expiry of its purpose if it is authorised by law (in particular to protect Ringaling.tv's interests, e.g. if it believes on reasonable grounds that You have failed to fulfil your undertakings to Ringaling.tv or have committed a breach of the criminal law). In these circumstances, Ringaling.tv will only retain PII while that situation is current, and will then destroy PII.

Communications

Ringaling.tv undertakes: 

  * to provide one or more channels for communications to Ringaling.tv, which are convenient to users;
  * to promptly provide acknowledgement of the receipt of communications, including the provision of a copy of the communication, the date and time it was registered, and Ringaling.tv's reference-code for the communication;
  * to promptly provide a response to the communication, in an appropriate and meaningful manner.  

Definitions 

Ringaling.tv means this website, www.ringaling.tv, and related websites, including mobile web (WAP) sites. 

PII (personally identifiable information) means data that is capable of being associated with you, whether or not it includes an explicit identifier such as your name or customer number. In particular, it encompasses all data that Ringaling.tv is capable of correlating with you, using such means as server-logs and cookie-contents.

PII does not refer to data that can no longer be associated with you. This includes aggregated data that does not and cannot identify the individuals whose data are included in the aggregation. 

Consent means your concurrence with an action to be taken by Ringaling.tv. Consent may be express or implicit, but in either case must be informed and freely-given.

Glossary of technical terms used

Web browser  
The piece of software you use to read web pages. Examples are Microsoft Internet Explorer, Firefox, Netscape Navigator and Opera.

IP address  
The identifying details for your computer (or your internet company's computer), expressed in "internet protocol" code (for example 192.168.13.34). Every computer connected to the web has a unique IP address, although the address may not be the same every time a connection is made.

Cookies  
Small pieces of information, stored in simple text files, placed on your computer by a web site. Cookies can be read by the web site on your subsequent visits. The information stored in a cookie may relate to your browsing habits on the web page, or a unique identification number so that the web site can "remember" you on your return visit. Generally speaking, cookies do not contain personal information from which you can be identified, unless you have furnished such information to the web site.

Questions or Comments

If you wish to enquire about any matter in relation to this Privacy Statement or our processing of your personal data, please feel free to contact us.

Please also read the Terms and Conditions.
